Bhavesh Narsai

Experienced IT professional specializing in technical support, IT development and project management with the ability to adapt to a wide array of fast-paced work environment. An honest and keen individual with a broad range of skills and technical experience. Very proactive approach to all situations and focus on delivering exceptional customer service.

07718273958

bnarsai90@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

NCC Group, Manchester — *Independent Build Verification Consultant*

March 2019 - Present

Operating as part of a dedicated team to create build environments to ensure that software applications can be rebuilt from their component source code in an independent secure test laboratory.

- Gathering information via technical reports, questionnaires and pre-sale scoping calls to identify the technology stack required to recreate a build environment
- Procuring and organising the purchase of any third party software, software licenses or utilities to create a build environment.
- Creating and ensuring a complete list of third party software development tools are available to the team.
- Setting up virtual build machines to transform source code into an executable format.
- Liaising directly with software vendors and licensees to troubleshoot and resolve any problems encountered during the build process and testing.
- Producing a technical report containing the key information to rebuild software.

NCC Group, Manchester — Verification Consultant

November 2015 - March 2019

Visiting UK and global client sites, to audit and document the process required to build and deploy software applications from their component source code.

- Project management and delivery of various business continuity solutions and services.
- Collaboration alongside developers to understand and discuss the processes being documented.
- Delivering a strong customer focused service in an efficient and proactive manner
- Exposure to a vast array of build and deployment tools.
- Delivering high quality technical documentation.

NCC Group, Manchester — Integrity Test Analyst

December 2014 - November 2015

Integrity testing of standard deposits. Validation and verification of source code deposits in a fast paced environment.

- Processing customer deposits efficiently.
- Administration and technical support to client accounts on the external customer deposit portal.

SKILLS

1st, 2nd & 3rd Line technical support

Troubleshooting

Problem solving

Customer focused

Proactive

Team work

Adaptable

Project Management

skills

Software/Technical Documentation

Broad knowledge of operating systems and platform development tools

Software Development

Lifecycles(SDLC)

Databases(MySQL, SQL, Microsoft Access)

Microsoft Visual Studio

Programming(PHP, VB.NET, VBA)

Microsoft Office

Office 365

Active Directory

Networking

Social Media

Web Development(SEO,

- Logging of integrity test results in the corporate systems.
- Creation of client integrity test report.

Vita Cellular Foams, Middleton Manchester — *IT Data Analyst/Developer*

March 2014 - October 2014

Acting as a single point of contact to provide 3rd line support to internal staff for business applications.

- Developing bespoke applications and solutions within Visual Studio 2013 and Microsoft SQL databases.
- Creation of bespoke reports via crystal reports.
- Dealing with ad-hoc requests and providing solutions to simplify processes so they are more efficient.

Antler Ltd, Bury — IT support assistant

February 2013 - December 2013

Assisting using broad knowledge of IT infrastructure systems, providing 1st line technical support to antler stores and basic operational support to internal staff.

- Ensuring efficient operation of the network, administration and maintenance of servers, email, anti-spam and antivirus systems.
- Diagnosing and solving problems with computer systems in a timely manner.
- Coordinating system updates
- Processing nightly backups of Windows servers and data on the network.

Fujitsu, Bolton — Customer Service Technician

September 2012 - October 2012

Providing direct 1st line technical email and phone support to customers nationwide.

- Assisting customers with different problems and queries including password resets, account unlocks and service requests.
- Logging, prioritising, resolving incidents and progressing them until a resolution is reached.

Bolton School, Bolton — ICT Assistant

July 2010 - September 2010

Assisting within the IT helpdesk environment as an IT generalist.

- Data entry of computer asset data
- Installing, and updating new and old computer systems.
- Moving various ICT peripherals and hardware around the school.

EDUCATION

University Of Salford, Manchester — *BSc(Hons) Business Information Technology*

2009 - 2012

2:1

Bolton Sixth Form College North Campus, Bolton —

2008 - 2009

BTEC National Business studies – DD(equivalent to 2 A grade A-Levels) A2 ICT Grade C

HTML, CSS)

Windows, Mac, Linux

Virtual Machines

Cloud Computing

Microsoft Azure

INTEREST & HOBBIES

Technology

Emerging Technology

Gym

Football

Music

Reading

Travel

AS ICT Grade C GCSE Maths grade C

2006-2007

Studied GNVQ Business Studies for a year and obtained a Distinction grade (equivalent to 4 A's)
GCSE English grade C

CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES

July 2018

Cherryleaf Technical Author/Technical Writing (with Assessments) training course

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Full UK driving license

University - Delivered a group project as deputy team leader to construct a data support system for a company in the North West of the UK.

Delivered an extensive research project around the topic of social media marketing for small business enterprises for my final year dissertation.